Guide to the A. Arthur Schiller Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
A. Arthur Schiller Papers,
1897-1977.
Schiller, A. Arthur, 1902-1977.
ca. 30,000 items (64 boxes, 21 card file boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079309
Biographical Note
Abraham Arthur Schiller (1902-1977) was professor of law at Columbia University from 1928 until his death. He specialized in Roman law, African law, the law of developing countries, and military law. (Columbia University J.D., 1932).
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, notes, notebooks, photographs, printed materials, computer print-outs and tapes, key-punched cards, and card files of Schiller. The collection includes correspondence with his professional colleagues, foundations, and learned societies, and some personal correspondence. There are manuscripts and drafts of his books, articles, book reviews, lectures, and abstracts, his papers as a student, notebooks of readings and drafts, appointment books, mimeographed course materials, photostats, photographs, and materials relating to his computer studies of Roman law texts. Correspondents include Sir Harold Idris Bell, W.W. Buckland, W.E. Crum, Gilbert Highet, H.F. Jolowicz, Owen Lattimore, and Harold Medina.
Subjects
Columbia University--Faculty.; Bell, H. Idris (Harold Idris), Sir, b. 1879.; Buckland, W. W. (William Warwick), 1859-1946.; Crum, W. E. (Walter Ewing), 1865-1944.; Highet, Gilbert, 1906-1978.; Jolowicz, H. F.; Lattimore, Owen, 1900-1989.; Medina, Harold R. (Harold Raymond), 1888-1990.; Developing countries--Law and legislation.; Law--Study and teaching.; Roman law--Research.; Law--Africa.; Military law.; Law--Societies, etc.; Photoprints.; College teachers.; Lawyers.
Restrictions on Access
Boxes 2-65 of this collection are located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.This collection has no restrictions
Acquisition
1983 M-83 Schiller, Erna Kaske Gift
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondents
  - Barr, Stringfellow (Box 1)
  - Barzun, Jacques (Box 1)
  - Bell, Sir Harold Idris (Box 1)
  - Berle, Adolf Augustus, Jr. (Box 1)
  - Borton, Hugh (Box 1)
  - Buckland, William Warwick (Box 1)
  - Budge, Sir Ernest Alfred Thompson Wallis (Box 1)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray (Box 1)
  - Capart, Jean François (Box 1)
  - Chamberlain, Joseph Perkins (Box 1)
  - Crum, Walter Ewing (Box 1)
  - Douglas, William Orville (Box 1)
  - Ervin, Sam James, Jr. (Box 1)
  - Guidi, Ignazio (Box 1)
  - Hailey, Malcolm Hailey, Baron (Box 1)
  - Highet, Gilbert (Box 1)
  - Jackson, Abraham Valentine Wi1.liams (Box 1)
  - Jessup, Philip Caryl (Box 1)
  - Johnson, livin Saunders (Box 1)
  - Jolowicz, Herbert Felix (Box 1)
  - Lasker, Bruno (Box 1)
  - Lattimore, Owen (Box 1)
  - Lynd, Robert Staughton (Box 1)
  - Mabbott, Thomas Ollive (Box 1)
  - McMurray, Orrin Kip (Box 1)
  - Malone, Dumas (Box 1)
  - Medina, Harold R. (Box 1)
  - Meek, Charles Kingsley (Box 1)
  - Moon, Parker Thomas (Box 1)
  - Moore, John Bassett (Box 1)
  - Nelson, Benjamin Nathaniel (Box 1)
  - O'Leary, DeLacy Evans (Box 1)
  - Pound, Roscoe (Box 1)
  - Powciermaker, Hortense (Box 1)
  - Rogers, Lindsay (Box 1)
  - Rusk, Dean (Box 1)
  - Winlock, Herbert Eustis (Box 1)
- Series II: Uncataloged Correspondence
  - A -Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Abel, Richard (Box 2)
  - Allott, Anthony M. (Box 2)
  - Anderson, J. N. D. (Box 2)
  - Asante, Samuel K.B. (Box 2)
  - B (1) (Box 2)
  - B (2) (Box 2)
  - Beinart, Ben Z. (Box 2)
  - Berger, Adolf (Box 2)
  - Cass, Lucien (Box 2)
  - Caplan, Harry (Box 2)
  - Carrubba, Robert W. (Box 2)
  - Casson. Lionel (Box 2)
  - Chabot, H. (Box 2)
  - D (Box 3)
  - Daube, David (Box 3)
  - de Dominicis, Mario (Box 3)
  - Duff, Patrick W. (Box 3)
  - E (Box 3)
  - Erim (Box 3)
  - F (Box 3)
  - Feenstra, Robert (Box 3)
  - Finley, M. I. (Box 3)
  - G (Box 3)
  - Gilliam, J. Frank (Box 3)
  - Gluckman, Max (Box 3)
  - H (1) (Box 3)
  - H (2) (Box 3)
  - Hazard, John (Box 3)
  - I (Box 3)
  - J (Box 3)
  - K (1) (Box 4)
  - K (2) (Box 4)
  - Katzoff, Ranon (Box 4)
  - Keddy, Edwin (Box 4)
  - Kirschenbaum. Aaron (Box 4)
  - L (1) (Box 4)
  - L (2) (Box 4)
  - Levy, Ernst (Box 4)
  - Lewin, Julius (Box 4)
  - Lewis, Naphatali (Box 4)
  - Lubtow, Ulrich Von (Box 4)
  - M (1) (Box 4)
  - M (2) (Box 4)
  - Margadant, Guillermo Floris (Box 4)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art (Box 4)
  - Modrzejewski, Joseph (Box 4)
  - N (Box 5)
  - O (Box 5)
  - P-Q (1) (Box 5)
  - P-Q (2) (Box 5)
  - R (Box 5)
  - Radin, Max (Box 5)
  - Rheinstein, Max (Box 5)
  - S (1) (Box 5)
  - S (2) (Box 5)
  - Seidel, Erwin (Box 6)
  - Simon, Jean (Box 6)
  - Smith, Thomas B. (Box 6)
  - Stein, Peter (Box 6)
  - Steinwenter, Arthur (Box 6)
  - Supomo, R. (Box 6)
  - T (Box 6)
  - Thomas, J.A.C. (Box 6)
  - Thompson, Cliff F. (Box 6)
  - U (Box 6)
  - Unidentified (Box 6)
  - V (Box 6)
  - Volterra, Edoardo (Box 6)
  - W (1) (Box 6)
  - W (2) (Box 6)
  - Welles, C. Bradford (Box 6)
  - Wenger, Leopold (Box 6)
  - Wieacker, Franz (Box 6)
  - Worrell, William H. (Box 6)
  - y -Z (Box 6)
  - Yntema, Hessel E. (Box 6)
  - Youtie, Herbert (Box 6)
- Series III: Personal Files
  - A. Arthur Schiller (Box 7)
  - Correspondence A. Arthur Schiller (Box 7)
  - Correspondence re: Displaced and Oppressed Foreign Scholars late 30s early 40s (Box 7)
  - Family Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Family Correspondence Schiller, Mrs. George M. Estate of (Box 7)
  - Correspondence re: Schiller home in the Village of Larchmont (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous family documents (Box 7)
  - Letter to a Pagan Notable (Box 7)
  - Luncheon for Hays and Schiller (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous and family correspondence (Box 7)
  - Address Beaks (Box 7)
  - Appointment Books (Box 7)
  - Financial Books (Box 7)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous Mss., Lectures and Early Writing
  - Boston University Lecture (Box 8)
  - Early Writing and Lectures (Box 8)
  - Free University of Berlin (Box 8)
  - Interpretative Juris (Box 8)
  - Jurists Law (Box 8)
  - Legal Education, Univ. Istanbul (Box 8)
  - Mediaeval Classification (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous Lectures (Box 8)
  - Nature-of Jurists Law- (Box 8)
  - The Role of Roman Citizenship and Roman Law (Box 8)
  - Spanish Lecture 16th century Jurists (Box 8)
  - Manual of the stamps of Netherlands (Box 8)
  - Postmarks and cancellations of Curacao (Box 8)
  - Netherlands and Colonial Philately (Box 8)
- Series V: Manuscripts
  - Roman Law, am.s. (1) (Box 9)
  - Roman Law, am.s. (2) (Box 10)
  - Roman Law, am.s, (3) (Box 11)
  - Roman Law, Carbon Copy (Box 12)
  - Roman Law, Mimeograph Edition. 2nd Edition (1) (Box 13)
  - Roman Law, 2nd Edition (2) (Box 14)
- Series VI: Manuscripts Articles Book reviews with related Correspondence
  - Amelotti-Luzzatto Rev. (Box 15)
  - American Historical Review (Box 15)
  - American Journal of Comparative Law (Box 15)
  - American Journal of Legal History (Box 15)
  - American Scholarship in Roman Law (Box 15)
  - Bibliography of A. Arthur Schiller (Box 15)
  - Book Reviews (Box 15)
  - Book Reviews and Reprints 1928-1965 (Box 15)
  - Catholic Encyclopedia (Box 15)
  - Columbia Journal of Transnational Law (Box 15)
  - Copyright Forms (Box 15)
  - Encyclopedia Social Sciences (Box 15)
  - Istanbul Institute (Box 15)
  - Ivra (Box 15)
  - Jolowicz-Nicholas Rev. (Box 15)
  - Kaser-Rabel (Box 15)
  - Languages and their Relation (Box 15)
  - Lawgivers (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Publishing Correspondence (Box 16)
  - Miscellany (Box 16)
  - Ocena (Box 16)
  - Smith, Munroe (Box 16)
  - Social Science Abstracts (Box 16)
  - Studies in Legal History (Box 16)
  - West Publishing Company (Box 16)
  - Notebooks (numbered), 1-33 (Box 17)
- Series VII: Columbia University
  - Administration-Controller (Box 18)
  - Advisory Committee on Educational Policy (Box 18)
  - American Indian Law (Box 18)
  - ANC Mediterranean Studies (Box 18)
  - Appointments (Box 18)
  - Appointment Committee re Charles Donahue, Jr. (Box 18)
  - Bartolus Seminar (Box 18)
  - Civil Law Institute (Box 18)
  - Civil Law Institute Page 1-195 (Box 18)
  - Columbia Law Review (Box 18)
  - Computer Correspondence (Box 18)
  - Correspondence -Law Library (classification): (Box 19)
    - Correspondence (l) (Box 19)
    - Correspondence (2) (Box 19)
    - Course records of A. Schiller (Box 19)
    - Disturbances 1968 (Box 19)
    - Exam Question Sample (Box 19)
    - History Department (Box 19)
    - History of Legal and Political Thought (Box 19)
    - Law Library (Box 19)
    - Law Library Classification (1) (Box 19)
    - Law Library Classification (2) (Box 19)
  - Law Library Committee-Policies 1950/1 (Box 20)
  - Law of Trade Marks and Unfair Competition (1) (Box 20)
  - Law School (Box 20)
  - Library (Box 20)
  - McGil, William (Box 20)
  - N.D.E.A. Fellowship 1966/67 (Box 20)
  - School International Affairs 1966 (Box 20)
  - Sovern, Michael (Box 20)
  - University Seminar Bureaucracy (1) (Box 20)
  - University Seminar Bureaucracy (2) (Box 20)
  - Warren. William (Box 20)
- Series VIII: Foundations
  - Africa Ford Federation Correspondence (Box 21)
  - Brasilies-Guggenheim Project (Box 21)
  - Correspondence re Council for Research in the Social Science (Box 21)
  - Ford Foundation (1) (Box 21)
  - Ford-Foundation (2) (Box 21)
  - Foreign Academic Institute (Box 21)
  - Guggenheim Fellow (Box 21)
  - Guggenheim Foundation (Box 21)
  - International Legal Center (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous Foundation (Box 21)
  - Rockefeller (Box 21)
- Series IX: Learned Societies
  - Accademia Costantiniana (Box 22)
  - Accademia Nazionale Dei Lincei (Box 22)
  - Africa Conference Princeton University (Box 22)
  - American Assoc. of Law Libraries (Box 22)
  - American Assoc. of Univ. Professors (Box 22)
  - American Classical League (Box 22)
  - American Council Conference Law and Humanities (Box 22)
  - American Foreign Law Association (Box 22)
  - American History Association December 28. 1952 (Box 22)
  - American Research Center (Box 22)
  - American Research Center Egypt (Box 22)
  - American Society for Legal History (Box 22)
  - American Society for Legal History Meeting, September 73 (Box 22)
  - American Society for Legal History Meeting November 71 (Box 22)
  - American Society for Legal History Publisher Committee (Box 22)
  - American Society for Legal History Roman Law Conference (Box 22)
  - American Society of Papyrologists 1-5 (Box 22)
  - Ancient Civil Group (1) (Box 22)
  - Ancient Civil Group (2) (Box 22)
  - Asia Society Lecture (Box 22)
  - Association Internationale de Papyrologues (Box 22)
  - Association Papyrologues Providence (Box 22)
  - Association of American Law School (Box 22)
  - Association of American Law School Roman and African Law (Box 22)
  - Center for Research Libraries (Box 23)
  - Class Studies -Madrid September 1974 (Box 23)
  - Comité Internationale de Papyrologie (Box 23)
  - Conference of Jewish Relations -Correspondence (Box 23)
  - Conference of Jewish Relations -Immigration Study (Box 23)
  - Conference on Foreign Realtions 1-4 (Box 23)
  - Council for Research in Social Science 1-2 (Box 23)
  - Council for Research in Social Science -Roman Law (Box 23)
  - East Indies Institute of America (Box 23)
  - Foundation Egypt (Box 23)
  - International Africa Law Association (Box 23)
  - International Africa Law Association -Economic of African Law (Box 23)
  - International Association of Coptic Studies (Box 23)
  - International Association of Legal Science (Box 23)
  - International Commission of Jurists (Box 23)
  - International Juridical Organization (Box 23)
  - Institute for Advanced Study -Princeton (Box 23)
  - Institute for Comparative Lew -Uppsala 1966 (Box 23)
  - Institute of' Pacific Relations -Conference January 19~5Islamic (Box 23)
  - Culture Seminar (Box 23)
  - Learned Societies M -S (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 24)
  - Oriental Club (Box 24)
  - Parker School Conference (Box 24)
  - Riccobino Seminar 1-2 (Box 24)
  - Roman Law Congress -Mexico City (Box 24)
  - Roman Law Workshop (Box 24)
  - Social Science Research Correspondence (Box 24)
  - Societa Italians di Storia del Diritto (Box 24)
  - Societa Italians di Storia del Diritto - trip 1973 (Box 24)
  - Société D'Histories des Draits de l'Antiquite 1-5 (Box 24)
  - Société DeVisscher (Box 24)
  - Société Jean Bodin Meeting (Box 24)
  - Société meeting (Box 24)
  - Society for the Promotion of Roman Studies (Box 24)
- Series X; Papyri
  - Classic (Box 25)
  - Columbia (Box 25)
  - Columbia Coptic -Preliminary Reading (Box 25)
  - Columbia Coptic -with Lewis (Box 25)
  - Coptic (Box 25)
  - Council Project 1-2 (Box 25)
  - Demotic - Egyptian (Box 25)
  - Fineburg Odyssey (Box 25)
  - Greek Egyptian (Box 25)
  - Orientale (Box 25)
  - Papyri on Microfilm (Box 25)
  - Photo's of Papyri 1-2 (Box 25)
- Series XI: African Law Abel-African Law Material
  - Abel. Richard L. (Box 26)
  - Africa Law Bibliography (Box 26)
  - Africa. Maps (Box 26)
  - Africa Materials (Box 26)
  - Africa Miscellaneous (Box 26)
  - Africa Trip Correspondence 1959 (Box 26)
  - African Law Association in America Correspondence (Box 26)
  - African Law Association in America Directory (Box 26)
  - African Law Association in America Newsletter (Box 26)
  - African Law Center At Columbia University (Box 26)
  - African Law Center Project (Box 26)
  - African Law Center Publicity (Box 26)
  - African Law Correspondence and Materials (large format) (Box 26)
  - African Law Digest (Box 26)
  - African Law Lectures 1-2 (Box 26)
  - African. Law Material (1) (Box 26)
  - African Law Materials 2-3 (Box 27)
  - African Law Television (Box 27)
  - African Studies Association (Box 27)
  - African Studies Association Archives Libraries Committee 1-2 (Box 27)
  - African Studies Association Archives Libraries Committee 1965/67 (Box 27)
  - African Studies Association Archives Libraries Committee 1967 (Box 27)
  - African Studies Association Archives Libraries Committee Washington Meeting (Box 27)
  - African Studies Association Archives Libraries Committee Boxton Meeting (Box 27)
  - African Studies Association Correspondence 1-2 (Box 27)
  - African Studies Association Los Angles Meeting 1968 (Box 27)
  - African Studies Association New York Meeting 1967 (Box 27)
  - African Studies Association Political Sub-committee (Box 27)
  - Algeria Self-Government (Box 27)
  - Alphabet (Box 27)
  - Arrowhead Conference (Box 27)
  - Bentsi - Enchill (Box 28)
  - Bibliography (Box 28)
  - Bibliography of African Law in the Association of American Law School (Box 28)
  - Bibliography on Greek and Egyptian Papyri (Box 28)
  - Bibliography N.E.I. (Box 28)
  - Briefs (Box 28)
  - Bruce, John (Box 28)
  - Camp (Box 28)
  - Center for Research Libraries (Box 28)
  - Classification of Foreign Law Books (Box 28)
  - Cortini - Integration Law Somalia (Box 28)
  - Cooperative African Microfilm Project (Box 28)
  - Correspondence on African Law (Box 28)
  - Correspondence on Schiller, A.A. (Box 28)
  - Deutsche Institut für Afrika (Box 29)
  - East Africa Law Journal (Box 29)
  - East Indies Institute (Box 29)
  - East Landing Meeting (Box 29)
  - Encyclopedia of African Law (Box 29)
  - Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences (Box 29)
  - Eritrea (Box 29)
  - Eritrea -Correspondence and Speeches (Box 29)
  - Eritrean Customary Law (Box 29)
  - Eritrean 1-2 (Box 29)
  - Fetha Project Cordier (Box 29)
  - Formation of Federal Indonesia (Box 29)
  - Fulbright Africa (Box 29)
  - Future of African Law Center (Box 29)
  - Hopkins African Papers (Box 30)
  - Hopkins, Elizabeth (Box 30)
  - International African Law Association (Box 30)
  - International African Institute (Box 30)
  - Law of Adkeme Melegai (Box 30)
  - Julius Lewin (Box 30)
  - Library classification Africa (Box 30)
  - List of African Studies (Box 30)
  - Marriage and Family Law in East Africa (Box 30)
  - Members African Law Association in America (Box 30)
  - Milner, Alan (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 30)
  - Preface -Salacurs's Book (Box 31)
  - Primitive Law (Box 31)
  - Sailer Meeting September 9 (Box 31)
  - Jes Salacuse (Box 31)
  - Seminar on Africa (Box 31)
  - Seminar in African Law (Box 31)
  - Seminar in African Law 1-3 (Box 31)
  - Seminar in the Spring 1971 (Box 31)
  - Somali Peace Corps (Box 31)
  - South Africa Lectures 1968 (Box 31)
  - Thompson, Cliff (Box 31)
  - Unesco African Project (Box 31)
  - Univ. London Talk -Anderson (Box 31)
  - Xerox (Box 31)
- Series XII: Byzantine Egyptian Law; Coptic Law
  - Egyptian Law (Box 32)
  - Imperial Legislation (Box 32)
  - Imperial Legislation in late Byzantine Egypt 1-2 (Box 32)
  - Materials for Imperial Legislation (Box 32)
  - Volterra (Box 32)
  - Coptic Law Arbitration 1-3 (Box 32)
  - Ausstellung Kiptisch Kunst (Box 32)
  - British Museum (Box 33)
  - Budge Papyrus 1-2 (Box 33)
  - Columbia Coptica (Box 33)
  - Columbia Copica and Michigan Coptica (Box 33)
  - Columbia Coptica Publishing (Box 33)
  - Coptic Bibliography (Box 33)
  - Coptic Charm (Box 33)
  - Coptic Dictionary (Box 33)
  - Coptic Law English Version 1-3 (Box 33)
  - Coptic Law German Version 1-2 (Box 34)
  - Coptic Legal Papyrus (Box 34)
  - Coptic Names -Budge (Box 34)
  - Coptic Ostraca Brooklyn Museum (Box 34)
  - Coptic Ostraca Columbia University (Box 34)
  - Coptic Ostraca New York Historical Society (Box 34)
  - Coptic• Text (Box 34)
  - Coptic Texts (Box 34)
  - Coptic Words (Box 34)
  - Correspondence about Research Material (Box 34)
  - English Translation Coptic Law (Box 34)
  - English Translation Speculum reviews (Box 34)
  - F.C.D and Coptic Texts (Box 34)
  - Hephaistos (Box 34)
  - Introduction of Walter Ewing Crum (Box 34)
  - Legal Nature of the Narratio texts (Box 34)
  - Legal Rules and Economic Factors of Property in the Coptic Monasteries (Box 34)
  - Liber (Box 34)
  - Library Committee (Box 34)
  - List of Scholars (Box 34)
  - Methods of Investigation (Box 35)
  - Michigan Coptic Papyri (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Coptic Notes (Box 35)
  - Narratio Notes (Box 35)
  - Narratio Texts (Box 35)
  - No Court No Council (Box 35)
  - Plates Coptic Houses (Box 35)
  - Reflection on P. Yale (Box 35)
  - Shaort Articles (Box 35)
  - Studies Daube (Box 35)
  - Studies Hoebel (Box 35)
  - Studies Honor Khaddur (Box 35)
  - Till (Box 35)
  - Wisconsin Law review article and press (Box 35)
  - Youtie Fest Schrift (Box 35)
- Series XIII: Ethiopian Law
  - Agricultural Land Reform in Ethiopia (Box 36)
  - Contributo all Conoscenza del dirritto Consuetudinario (Box 36)
  - Costanzo (Box 36)
  - Customary Law Project (Box 36)
  - Ethiopia Project (Testa Zim) (Box 36)
  - Ethiopian (Box 36)
  - Ethiopian Application (Box 36)
  - Ethiopian Materials (Box 36)
  - Fisher's, Stanley Z. - Traditional Criminal Procedure in Ethopia -Land (Box 36)
  - Development and Reform in Ethiopia (Box 36)
  - Karnescim tentative classification (Box 37)
  - L'experience ethiopienne en matiére de Successions (Box 37)
  - Law of Saharti, Lamza, Nekerti and Danibo (Box 37)
  - Origins of Ethiopian Law (Box 37)
  - Photographs (Box 37)
  - Seraat Dembezun tentative (Box 37)
  - Serat Logociawo (Box 37)
  - Written Law of Habsellus, Ghebrekristos, Deketeshim (Box 37)
- Series XIV: Greek Law
  - Notebooks 1-12 (Box 38)
  - Notes on Greek and Roman Law with Bibliography on Jewish Law (Box 38)
- Series XV: Indonesian Law A-W; Military Law
  - Adat (Box 39)
  - Adat and Netherland East Indies Report (Box 39)
  - Adat Law circles and Native legal Communities (Box 39)
  - Adat Law notes (Box 39)
  - Geography and Adat Law-Chicago March 1951 (Box 39)
  - Ter Haar's book on Indonesian Adat (Box 39)
  - Dutch and Indonesian correspondence 1949-1950 (Box 39)
  - Indonesian Law Lecture notes for March 1954 (Box 39)
  - Microfilm materials Netherlands Indies-Indonesia (Box 39)
  - Netherlands Indies is divided (Box 39)
  - Netherlands East Indies Course (Box 39)
  - Outline for Netherlands East Indies Law (Box 39)
  - Project Council for Research in the Social Science (Box 39)
  - Project-IPR-Law and Government Indonesia (Box 39)
  - Social Science Research Council Application ~Jov. 1969 (Box 39)
  - Talks in Indonesia 1949-1950 (Box 39)
  - Volleuhoveu, Adat Law Circles and Native Legal Communities (Box 39)
  - War Resources of the Netherland East Indies (Box 39)
  - Military Law-Correspondence (Box 39)
  - Reviews of Texts on Military Law (Box 39)
- Series XVI: Roman Law
  - Abels, works and workmen in Rome (Box 40)
  - American Council Learned Socities-Roman Law Crum (Box 40)
  - American Council Learned Socities Roman Law Teaching (Box 40)
  - American Experience in Roman Law (Box 40)
  - American Experience -Sale (Box 40)
  - Anglo-American Bibliography of Roman Law (Box 40)
  - ANRW Study (Box 40)
  - Apokrimata 1-4 (Box 40)
  - Apokrimata-Letter (Box 40)
  - Apokrimata-Revision with Youtie (Box 40)
  - Arbitration and Adjudication (Box 40)
  - Architectural terms in Digest (Box 40)
  - Association of American Law Schools (Box 40)
  - Basilica materials (Box 41)
  - Bibliography and Classification of Ancient Roman Lae (Box 41)
  - Bibliography Publication (Box 41)
  - Budge. Papyrus. for Jarce (Box 41)
  - Bureaucracy Bibliography (Box 41)
  - Bureaucracy in the Roman Principate (Box 41)
  - Byzantine Papyri (Box 41)
  - Cases of Resolution of Controversies Discovered in Julian (Box 41)
  - Civil Law Institutions (Box 41)
  - Civil Law Institutions 1-2 (Box 41)
  - Civil Procedure with class notes (Box 42)
  - Chapter XII-XIII (Box 42)
  - Collected Digest Materials (Box 42)
  - Collected Works Publication (Box 42)
  - Collected Works Reviews (Box 42)
  - Comparative Law Congress 1-2 (Box 42)
  - Computer Projects (Box 42)
  - Correspondence Courts are No More (Box 42)
  - Crum, W.E. (Box 42)
  - Crum materia1s re Introduction (Box 42)
  - Current (Box 42)
  - Custom in Roman Classical Law (Box 42)
  - Digest XIX.2-translation (Box 42)
  - Encyclopedia of Social Science (Box 42)
  - Family Archive from Jeme (Box 42)
  - Festschrift Oertel (Box 43)
  - Festschrift David (Box 43)
  - Festschrift Seidl (Box 43)
  - Festschrift Von Lübtow (Box 43)
  - Imperial Legislation (Box 43)
  - Interpreatatio Iuris (Box 43)
  - Jurists and the Praefects of the City (Box 43)
  - Jurists and the Praefects of !1:o!lle 1-2 (Box 43)
  - Levtures (Box 43)
  - Levy, Ernst (Box 43)
  - Lex Aquilia-C1ass Spring 1937 (Box 43)
  - Medieval Law (Box 43)
  - New York Univ. Lecture on Roman Law (Box 43)
  - Notebooks (Box 43)
  - Notes on Roman Law (Box 43)
  - Notes on Roman Law and Classical Law (Box 43)
  - Permission for Republication (Box 44)
  - Perugia Talk (Box 44)
  - Proposal re Undergraduate Gourde in Roman Law (Box 44)
  - Publish Roman Law Book (Box 44)
  - Riccobono Lecture (Box 44)
  - Reviews of Articles on Roman Law (Box 44)
  - Roman Bureaucracy (Box 44)
  - Roman Law Syllabus (Box 44)
  - Sale of Roman Law Books (Box 44)
  - Schecter, Martha (Box 44)
  - Studi in Onore di Giuseppe Grosso (Box 44)
  - Studies in Caplan (Box 44)
  - Survey of the Roman Law (Box 44)
  - Tabula Banasitana (Box 44)
  - Tabula Banasitana Oriental Club (Box 44)
  - Tabula Banasitana Washington Oriental Club (Box 44)
  - Texts and Commentary Book III Classical Law (Box 44)
  - Thirteen Reponsa of Septimius Severus (Box 44)
  - Vindication of repudiated text-Venice Speech (Box 44)
  - Vulgar Law-Labeo (Box 44)
- Series XVII: Computer Projects
  - General Files (Box 45)
  - Brockport Computer Conference (Box 45)
  - Columbia Computer Center Materials (Box 45)
  - Computer Correspondence Center Project Abstract 1971-1972 (Box 45)
  - Computer and Humanities (Box 45)
  - Computer Project (Box 45)
  - Computer Project for Venice (Box 45)
  - African Concordance (Box 46)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 46)
  - Valeus Concordance (Box 46)